Guide to the New York agricultural leaders oral history project, 1962-1968.
New York agricultural leaders oral history project
- Series I. First Alphabetical Sequence (with descriptions)
  - Huttar, John C., 1902-1988, November 24, 1964; Transcript #123 (Box 4)
    Description: Student experiences at Cornell, esp. research for Ph.D.; recollections concerning James Rice, Earl Benjamin; experiences managing poultry farms in New Jersey, 1931-1932; experiences with GLF and Agway, 1933-1965, especially marking eggs in New York City; introduction of contracts with egg producers; GLF management training programs; poultry service work; work as farm reporter on Rural Radio Network; egg buyer for USDA; observations concerning organization and activities of National Poultry Industry Planning Committee, Poultry and Egg National Board, New York State Poultry Council, Northeastern Poultry Producers Council; relationships between poultry producer organizations; adjustments required for survival in the poultry industry.
  - Jennings, Burton Aaron, 1895-1964, February 7, 1963; Transcript #28 (Box 1)
    Occupation: Agricultural Engineering professor
    Description: Student experiences at Cornell; impressions of George F. Warren and William Barrett; work of Dept. of Farm Practice; teaching and extension in agricultural engineering
  - King, Asa Carlton and, 1877-1967, October 12, 1962; Transcript #12 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: 1899
    Occupation: Educational administrator
    Description: The objectives and administration of the farm practice requirement at Cornell, 1915-1950.
    See also collection # 37-5-3637
  - Gibson, Anson Wright, 1892-1977, Undated; Transcript #12 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: 1917
    Description: Childhood experiences; farming in Cayuga County in the 1890s; experiences as a student at Cornell; impressions of Carl Ladd, E. O. Fippin, George Everett, William H. Chandler, L. H. Bailey, George F. Warren; extension work in pomology, 1915; establishing the New York State School of Agriculture at Cobleskill, NY, 1916-1921; experiences as director NYS Agricultural and Technical Institute at Farmingdale, especially relationships to Long Island agricultural organizations, determining teaching objectives, curriculum development, financial support; experiences as project leader, Cornell-Los Banos Project, 1957-1960, especially relationships to I.C.A. and to the staff of the College of Agriculture at Los Banos, living conditions.
    See also collection # 21-1-2290
  - Knapp, Halsey, 1888-1976, July 12, 1963; Transcript #126 (Box 5)
    Cornell Class: 1912, MS 1913
    Description: Student experiences at Cornell; land utilization work in the Dept. of Agricultural Economics at Cornell; recollections concerning George F. Warren; development of fruit marketing cooperatives in Western New York.
    See also collection # 21-2-1700
  - LaMont, Thomas E., 1906-1970, November 21, 1962; Transcript #19 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: 1927, MS 1928, PhD
    Description: Graduate study at Cornell; development of Laboratory of Animal Nutrition at Cornell; graduate instruction in nutrition; research problems; observations on nutrition work at other institutions in the 1920s; open formula feeds, other work with GLF; administration of U.S. Plant, Soil, and Nutrition Laboratory at Cornell; development and administration of Dept. of Biochemistry and School of Nutrition at Cornell; observations on nutrition in China, England, other countries; impressions of H. H. Wing, E. S. Savage, A. R. Mann, Lewis Knudson, H. E. Babcock.
  - Maynard, L.A. (Leonard Amby), 1887-1972, February 19, 1963; Transcript #31 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: PhD 1915
    Occupation: Nutrition professor
    Description: Student experiences at Cornell, especially employment on George F. Warren’s farm; work in Dept. of Animal Husbandry; development of GLF feed service; major decisions in development of GLF; relationships of GLF to agricultural colleges and to other businesses; contributions of H. E. Babcock to GLF. Also, with Bruce Gervan, development of GLF information and public relations programs; Rural Radio Network; relationships of GLF to farm organizations; expansion of GLF territory; National Council of Farm Cooperatives.
    See also collection # 29-1-292
  - McConnell, James, 1891-1974, October 5, 1962; Transcript #62 (Box 2)
    Cornell Class: 1921
  - and Gervan, R. Bruce, 1907-1993?, December 11, 1963; Transcript #62 (Box 2)
    Occupation: Businessman GLF
    Description:
  - Milliman, Thomas E., 1890-1971, February 25, 1964; Transcript #5157 (Box 40)
    Description: Early farm experiences, education at Cornell; impressions of the faculty of the College of Agriculture; experiences as farm manager on Long Island and as agricultural agent in Orange County, NY; participation in the Dairymen’s League strike, 1916, and in the Wicks Committee investigation.
  - Milliman, Thomas E., 1890-1971, Addition, August 24, 1967; Transcript #5158 (Box 40)
  - Monroe, Benton Sullivan, 1873-1968, September 11, 1962; Transcript #7 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: 1896, MA 1897, PhD 1901
    Occupation: English professor
    Description: Reminiscences concerning Cornell faculty members, 1890-1920.
    See also collection # 41-12-1356
  - Munger, Harlan B., 1888-1969, February 27, 1963; Transcript #20 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: 1912
    Occupation: Farm credit administrator
    Description: Student experiences at Cornell; recollections concerning George F. Warren; farm management surveys with USDA; teaching farm management at Iowa State College and at farmers’ institutes in New York State; farm appraisal work for Federal Land Bank; development of production credit associations in Springfield district; relationships between administration of land and short term credit.
  - Myers, William Irving, 1891-1976, April 25, 1964; Transcript #497 (Box 10)
    Occupation: Dean, College of Agriculture
    Description: Education and family experiences in Chemung County, NY; education at Cornell; summer jobs and other work experiences; graduate study at Cornell; farm layout study; participation in early farm management surveys; expansion of staff and curriculum in agricultural economics at Cornell, 1918-1933; development of extension work in agricultural credit; county conference committees; work with GLF; impressions of H. E. Babcock, K. C. Livermore, George F. Warren.
    See also collection # 21-2-466
  - Norton, Horace W., 1883-1971?, January 30, 1963; Transcript #17 (Box 1)
    Occupation: Dairy association official
    Description: Activities with Holstein-Friesian Association, 1919-1958; establishing standards for quality in dairy cattle; recollections concerning H. H. Wing; the Cabana case.
  - Palmer, E. Laurence (Ephraim Laurence), 1888-1970, February 1, 1963; Transcript #30 (Box 1)
    Occupation: Education professor
    Description: School experiences; reflections concerning boyhood of Carl E. Ladd; graduate study at Cornell; experiences at Iowa State Teachers College; nature study at Cornell; reflections on National Association for Research and Science Teaching; preparation of Fieldbook of Natural History; development of Dept. of Conservation at Cornell; impressions of W. W. Rowlee; James Needham; Anna B. Comstock, Alice McCloskey, George Works, others.
  - Palmer, E. Laurence (Ephraim Laurence), 1888-1970, Addition, January 12, 1967; Transcript #30 (Box 1)
    Interviewer: Adair
  - Riley, Howard W., 1879-1971, August 15, 1963; Transcript #79 (Box 3)
    Description: Farm experiences in New Jersey; development of agricultural engineering at Cornell, 1907-1930s; experiences with early gasoline engines; development of septic tank systems and home water systems; development of testing devices and teaching aids; participation in Christian Science Society.
  - Rodenhurst, Seymour K., 1893-1979, November 10, 1964; Transcript #134 (Box 5)
    Description: Experiences as a dairy farmer in Jefferson County, NY, 1898-1965; farm management practices, rural recreation, 1920s; participation in milk strikes; experiences as director, Dairymen’s League, 1942-1961, and as member of the executive committee, 1945-1949 and 1953-1961; passage of milk control legislation and administration of state and federal milk control; impressions of Fred Sexauer and other League presidents.
  - Shapley, S. Reuben, 1906-1997, February 14, 1963; Transcript #27 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: 1928
    Description: Student experiences at Cornell; county agent work in Genesee and Columbia Counties; war labor program; administration of the student practice requirement at Cornell.
  - Simons, Lloyd R. (L.R.), 1886-1978, April 8, 1963; Transcript #43 (Box 2)
    Cornell Class: 1911
    Occupation: Extension professor
    Description: Childhood experiences; student experiences at Cornell; establishing Farm Bureau in Nassau County; work with Federal Extension Office during World War I; formation of American Farm Bureau Federation; experiences as assistant county agent leader, county agent leader, and director of extension at Cornell, especially relating to extension methods, extension specialists, and relationships to farm organization; reminiscences concerning C. B. Smith, Carl Ladd, Fred Freestone, Fred Sexauer, H. E. Babcock, Louis Taber, Albert S. Goss, Ed O’Neal, Earl Smith; experiences in Washington relating to administration of New Deal agricultural programs; separation of Farm Bureau and Extension Service in New York; comments on scope of extension work in New York.
    See also collection # 21-24-108
  - Slack, Clarence M., 1894-1976, February 20, 1964; Transcript #52 (Box 2)
    Cornell Class: 1916
    Description: Education at Cornell; experiences as county agricultural agent in Washington County, NY, 1924-1955; dairy cattle judging; dairy herd improvement programs; evaluation of breed associations, other agricultural organizations in county.
  - Smith, Paul, 1889-, November 10, 1964; Transcript #129 (Box 5)
    Description: Rural economic and social activities, Tioga County, NY, 1920-1964; milk marketing, esp. 1916 strike and Dairymen’s League activities; farmers’ reaction to TB testing; comments on need for government regulation of agriculture; experiences as director, New York State Fair, 1938-1941, and as Assistant Commissioner of Agriculture and Markets, N.Y.S.; relationships to milk market administrator, to Extension Service, and to Farm Bureau.
  - Stempfle, William Secord, 1895-1982, April 22, 1964; Transcript #234 (Box 7)
    Cornell Class: 1920
    Occupation: Farm organization representative
    Description: Experiences as county agricultural agent in Oneida County, NY and Steuben County, NY, especially efforts to secure committeeman, TB eradication, work with potato growers; comments concerning H. E. Babcock and George F. Warren.
  - Stiles, Jared W., 1907-1974, December 5, 1963; Transcript #102 (Box 3)
    Cornell Class: 1929
    Description: Agriculture in Lewis County, NY, 1915-1920; student activities at Cornell; comments on member of faculty and administration, especially A. R. Mann, George F. Warren, W. I. Myers, Charles Allen; reminiscences concerning V. A. Fogg, H. E. Babcock, James McConnell; development of GLF, 1920-1964, especially relations to patrons and competitors, committee system, strike at Buffalo mill, effect of World War II, reorganizations, employee selection and training, research program and its role in northeastern agriculture, P. & C.; formation of Agway.
  - Tailby, George W., 1882-1965, December 10, 1962; Transcript #32 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: 1906
    Occupation: Superintendent of Livestock
    Description: Extension specialist. Activities of campus children at Cornell in the 1890s; hauling coal at the University; the Roberts Barn; recollections concerning I. P. Roberts, H. H. Wing, L. H. Bailey.
  - Taylor, Clayton Charles, Jr., 1898-1979, July 9, 1963; Transcript #35 (Box 1)
    Description: Student experiences at Cornell; reflections concerning his father’s farming; development of farm operation based on purebred Angus, Concord grapes, and production of feeder pigs; comments on Erie County Farm Bureau, Erie County Fair, and Erie County agriculture.
  - Thomson, Edward Hermann, 1887-1967, May 27, 1963; Transcript #51 (Box 2)
    Cornell Class: 1909, MS 1911
    Occupation: Banker
    Description: Farm experiences in Delaware County; student experiences at Cornell; early farm management surveys; work in Office of Farm Management USDA; activities as Federal Land Bank of Springfield; coordination of activities of land banks; recollections of George F. Warren, W. J. Spillman, B. T. Galloway.
  - Thompson, Homer C., 1885-1976, October 9, 1963; Transcript #65 (Box 2)
    Occupation: Horticulture professor
    Description: Education at Ohio State University; work in farm management and horticulture, USDA, especially field investigations in rice, peanuts, sweet potatoes, celery; development of Dept. of Vegetable Crops at Cornell, 1918-1951; impressions of B. T. Galloway, T. L. Lyon, E. O. Fippin, R. A. Emerson, W. A. Chandler, George F. Warren, George Works, Paul Kruse, E. L. Worthen, C. E Ladd, others; establishment of Long Island Vegetable Research Farm; relationships between research and extension work in vegetable crops, particularly coordination with other departments at Ithaca and Geneva; reflections concerning outstanding vegetable growers in New York State; administration of Dept. of Vegetable Crops at Cornell; experiences as head, Bureau of Plant Industry, International Institute of Agricultural Sciences, Costa Rica.
  - Underwood, E. Victor, 1889-1974, November 14, 1962; Transcript #13 (Box 1)
    Description: Experiences as student at Cornell and agricultural agent in Oswego and Erie Counties; activities in Albany on behalf of the New York State Farm Bureau Federation and the Conference Board of Farm Organizations; fundraising for GLF; recollections of H. E. Babcock, M. C. Burritt, G. F. Warren; 1909-1960.
  - Wadsworth, Reverdy Johnson, 1914-1970, November 21, 1963; Transcript #45 (Box 2)
    Description: Education, farm operations of his father James Wadsworth, 1925-1940; experiences as cattle driver and grader, Chicago stockyards, 1937; management of beef and dairy cattle farms in Geneseo, 1938-1963; description of rented farms; implementation of provisions of lease; status of tenant in community; tenure.
  - Wadsworth, William P., 1906-1982, December 6, 1963; Transcript #44 (Box 2)
    Description: Education; organization and operation of farms at Geneseo, NY, 1915-1963, including processing and marketing orchard products, production and marketing of beef, sources of agricultural information; description of farms rented; implementation of provisions of lease; tenure of renters; relationships to tenants; problems of property maintenance.
  - Wakely, Philip Carman, 1902-1983, March 24, 1965; Transcript #143 (Box 5)
    Cornell Class: 1923
    Description: Childhood education; family activities; early interest in forestry; student experiences in Dept. of Forestry at Cornell; reflections on professionalism and Yale influence of forestry education at Cornell; experiences at Southern Forestry Experiment Station, esp. regeneration studies, commercial interests in reforestation, relations between administrators and researchers in Forest Service; development of pulpwood industry in South; recollections concerning Bristow Adams, Samuel Spring, Ralph Hosmer, A. B. Recknagle, Cedric Guise, Lane Cooper, Ed Munns, F. O. Bateman, Austin Cary, and W. W. Ashe.
  - Waldorf, William E. and, 1916-2000, May 18, 1965; Transcript #200 (Box 6)
    Description: Experiences in acquiring ownership of dairy farm in Columbia County, NY; efforts to understand milk pricing; experiences organizing farmers to obtain milk price increases, esp. organizing Dairy Farmers of America; reaction of existing farm organizations to his activities. David Osofsky also participated in the interview.
  - Osofsky, David, 1914-1997, May 18, 1965; Transcript #200 (Box 6)
  - Warren, Carl, February 15, 1963; Transcript #23 (Box 1)
    Occupation: Seedsman
    Description: Seed business in New York State, 1910; organization and operation of the Joseph Harris Company, 1920-1960, especially origin of new varieties, work of seed salesmen; New York State Seed Association; contribution of Cornell University to seed development and distribution.
  - Worthen, Edmund L., 1882-1965, August 29, 1962; Transcript #1 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: MS 1908
    Occupation: Agronomy Extension
    Description: Extension work of the Dept. of Agronomy at Cornell, 1919-1950, especially introduction of superphosphate and high-analysis fertilizers.
- Series II. Second Alphabetical Sequence (without descriptions)
  - Blanchard, Albert, 1899-1970, October 22, 1964; Transcript #114 (Box 4)
    Cornell Class: 1926
  - Clickman, Walter, 1875-1970, January 31, 1968; Transcript #255 (Box 7)
    Interviewer: Levine
  - Colton, William L., 1890-1977, February 2, 1968; Transcript #256 (Box 7)
  - Corwith, James C., 1895-1966, June 22, 1965; Transcript #136 (Box 5)
  - Giffin, Walter, 1894-1978, January 31, 1968; Transcript #282 (Box 8)
  - Hartwig, Herbert B., 1898-1967, June 30, 1965; Transcript #137 (Box 5)
    See also collection # 21-12-2078
  - Hitchings, Raymond C., 1892-1977, January 15, 1965; Transcript #142 (Box 5)
    Occupation: Farmer, USDA seed program
  - Lamb, George, 1891-1985, February 12, 1966; Transcript #179 (Box 6)
  - MacDaniels, Laurence H., 1888-1986, February 7, 1966; Transcript #218 (Box 7)
    Occupation: Floriculture professor
    See also collection # 21-25-815
  - MacDonald, Elizabeth, 1876-1972, July 11, 1967; Transcript #219 (Box 7)
    See also collection # 1069, 13-6-428
  - Raish, Edgar, 1884-1970, December 30, 1964; Transcript #122 (Box 4)
  - Ross, Orrin, 1885-1974, December 16, 1964; Transcript #118 (Box 4)
    Cornell Class: Spring Agriculture 1908
  - Rumsey, Fred D., 1870-1967, February 22, 1963; Transcript #29 (Box 1)
    See also collection # 2877
  - Scoville, G. P. (Gad Parker), 1885, 1885-1971, September 11, 1964; Transcript #101 (Box 3)
    Cornell Class: 1910
    Occupation: Pomology professor
  - Stanley, Harold M., 1891-1975, September 20, 1963; Transcript #41 (Box 2)
    Occupation: State Grange secretary
  - Wright, Albert H., 1879-1970, December 19, 1962; Transcript #22 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: 1904, MA 1905, PhD 1908
    Occupation: Zoology professor
    See also collection # 14-26-1382
  - Wright, Anna, 1882-1964, December 19, 1962; Transcript #22 (Box 1)
    Cornell Class: 1909